# JOHN SNOW

# **EDUCATION**

## Indian Institute of Technology, Gandhinagar

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer.

July 2016 - May 2020

Overall CGPA: 9.05

## CAREER OBJECTIVE

To work for an organization which provides me the opportunity to improve my skills and knowledge to grow along with the organization objective.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### GitHub Notifier

This project aims at providing real time information of events from GitHub and notify you accordingly. The project is in ready-to-deployment stage on a demo server as a cron-job. The notification engine used for real time tracking is completely based on the python implementation assembled in an Android App with firebase cloud support.

#### GitHub Notifier

This project aims at providing real time information of events from GitHub and notify you accordingly. The project is in ready-to-deployment stage on a demo server as a cron-job. The notification engine used for real time tracking is completely based on the python implementation assembled in an Android App with firebase cloud support.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Languages C, C++, Python, Java, C#

**Technologies** MVC, HTM

Tools MikTex, Kil

Databases MySql, Orac Cloud Technologies Firebase, AV

Version Control Github



## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Reversible Alphabet Pvt. Ltd., India

Data Scientist

- · Created classification models for e-commerce websites using neural networks.
- · Achieved exposure towards classification optimalization techniques for further specialization.
- · Worked under an experenced Data Scientist and got deep insights related to optimization algorithms.

## Irreversible Alphabet Pvt. Ltd., India

Data Scientist

Jun 2016 - Dec 2016

Jun 2017 - Dec 2018

- · Created classification models for e-commerce websites using neural networks.
- · Achieved exposure towards classification optimaization techniques for further specialization.
- · Worked under an experenced Data Scientist and got deep insights related to optimization algorithms.

#### ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

Project 'XYZ' won Best Project under Environmental Solver category under AICTE, Government of India

Recieved Scholarship For Higher Education(She) Component Under Inspire Scheme worth INR 4,00,000

Achived A Grade in Diploma in Computer Science from IBM

Won First Prize in Zonal technical quiz Competition Organized by IIT, Mumbai.

Project 'XYZ' won Best Project under Environmental Solver category under AICTE, Government of India

Recieved Scholarship For Higher Education(She) Component Under Inspire Scheme worth INR 4,00,000

Achived A Grade in Diploma in Computer Science from IBM

Won First Prize in Zonal technical quiz Competition Organized by IIT, Mumbai.

## **EXTRA-CIRRUCULAR**

Attended a workshop on Machine Learning and artificial intelligence from faculties of IIT Roorkee in 2019 and won zonal round for the challenge presented.

Member of the Institute of Engineers since 2017.

Completed Basic Leadership Training under Project NSS, Gujarat

Attended a workshop on Machine Learning and artificial intelligence from faculties of IIT Roorkee in 2019 and won zonal round for the challenge presented.

Member of the Institute of Engineers since 2017.

Completed Basic Leadership Training under Project NSS, Gujarat

Attended a workshop on Machine Learr 2019 and won zonal round for the challe

Member of the Institute of Engineers sir

Completed Basic Leadership Training un



ntelligence from faculties of IIT Roorkee in

Gujarat

## RESEARCH PROFILE

Student President, Technology and Research, IIT Gandhinagar

Publication: ABC, IOT IEEE Transactions (Impact Factor: 9.3, Status: Published)

Student President, Technology and Research, IIT Gandhinagar

Publication: ABC, IOT IEEE Transactions (Impact Factor: 9.3, Status: Published)

Student President, Technology and Research, IIT Gandhinagar

Publication: ABC, IOT IEEE Transactions (Impact Factor: 9.3, Status: Published)